<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>homeless bits</title><link href="http://louiedinh.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://louiedinh.github.io/feeds/personal-mba.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://louiedinh.github.io/</id><updated>2013-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Choose Yourself</title><link href="http://louiedinh.github.io/choose-yourself.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Louie Dinh</name></author><id>tag:louiedinh.github.io,2013-08-12:choose-yourself.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In James Altucher's eye opening book, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1490313370/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1490313370&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=homebits04-20"&gt;Choose Yourself&lt;/a&gt;, teaches you 
how to deal with the new economy. The shifting world of work is
already at our feet and James has given us a map to navigate with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Old Institutions Are Dead. Choose Yourself.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old institutions are dead, and with it is the promise of job security.
A college degree is no longer a golden ticket to a middle class lifestyle. 
Software is eating the world, starting with the middle class paper pushers.
The squeeze in the middle is forcing labour to pop out both ends. 
Either you level up and come out on top as an entrepreneur, or you are made
redundant by software and become a temp staffer/gun for hire. Take your pick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s when it clicked. When everything changed. When I realized that
nobody else was going to do it for me. If I was going to thrive, to
survive, I had to choose myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new economy isn't really new. We're just seeing the hollowing out of the
middle bit. The top has always consisted of trail blazers, independent 
thinkers and artists. The bottom has always been populated by interchangable
labor and temporary staffers. The only difference is that now you can't settle
comfortably in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must be a creator, innovator, artist, investor, marketer AND
entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To succeed you must, in James' words, light your inner fire. "Meh",
is your greatest enemy. A "meh" job will not inspire you to challenge
the status quo and unleash your potential on the world.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You light your fire by building up a foundation of health and then 
feeding the fire to stimulate your creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You light your fire by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only do things that you enjoy. Only think about the people you
enjoy. Only read the books you enjoy that make you happy to be
human. Only go to events that actually make you laugh or fall in
love. Only deal with people hwo love you back and who are winners and
want you to win too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everytime you say yes to something that you don't want to do, this
will happen to you: you will resent people, you will do a bad job, you
will have less energy for the things you were doing a good job on, you
will make less money, and yet another small percentage of your life
will be used up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start With a Daily Practice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The daily practice is a set of activities that ensure the health of
your four beings: physical, mental, emotional, and spiritual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some practical tips are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip TV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surprise someone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be grateful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a ton of other great tips in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unleashing Your Inner Entrepreneur&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is an entrepreneur. The only skills you need to be an
entrepreneur are the ability to fail, to have ideas, to sell those
ideas, to execute on them, and to be persistent so even as you fail
you learn and move onto the next adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abundance will never come from your job. Abundance only comes when you
are moving along your themes. When you are truly enhancig the lives of
the people around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where To Start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a boring business. Then do it slightly better then everybody else. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut out the middle man and deliver value directly to your customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start blogging to build up trust while you sleep. This will lead to opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say yes when an opportunity arises. Take it and run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treat everyone like a human being.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making a Million Dollars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporate America doesn't solve problems. It churns out the same
product with minor tweaks forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School doesn't teach you how to come up with ideas. School doesn't
teach you how to sell those ideas. School doesn't teach you how to
bounce back once you've failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Messaging someone to ask for help = valuing their time at zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Study the history of the form you want to master. Study every
nuance. If you want to write, read not only all of your
contemporaries, but the influences of those contemporaries, and their
influences. Additionally, draw inspiration from other art forms. Then
go back. The facets that resonate with time, even if it's hundreds of
years old, will resonate with your work as well. It's like a law of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on what you can do for your art/business right now instead
of trying to aim for 10 years from now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can release other stuff on your outlet. It doesn't have to always
be your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick a social media outlet and MASTER IT. This is you
platform. Mastery of both your art and your distribution is the only
way to win&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><category term="personal-mba/readings"></category></entry><entry><title>The Personal MBA</title><link href="http://louiedinh.github.io/personal-mba.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Louie Dinh</name></author><id>tag:louiedinh.github.io,2013-08-10:personal-mba.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Personal MBA&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal-mba/readings"></category></entry></feed>